DEVENDRA SINGH

DEPUTY MANAGER __



Contacts

- +91-8359895218
- devendra.fe@gmail.com

441 M P/199A, Sevapuram,

- JalNigam Road, Balaganj, Lucknow
- https://devendra616.github.io/ portfolio/

Skills

- React NodeJs MongoDb
- Express HTML5
- Javascript Java
- ASP.NET
- IBM Blade Servers

Profile

Web application developer (MERN stack) with a flair for creating elegant solutions with in the time. Technically sound professional with over 5+ years of experience in the area of software development, designing and developing user interfaces, debugging and deploying application. Self-motivated and constant learner able to create responsive web applications from scratch till final deployment. Capable of working in small, medium and large teams.

Experience

Deputy Manager NMDC Ltd

Sep 2015 - Present

Kirandul

- Designing, development, and implementation of Web Applications based on user requirements.
- Maintaining and improving existing applications.
- Development and up-gradation of local website (intranet).
- · Attending user's issues on HRMS, IMS, FAS, ARS.
- Applications Developed: File Tracking System, Hourly Production, Incentive
- Package, HRMS Dashboard, Quarter Allotment System, Complaint Recording System, Production Package, Hospital Pathology Sample Recording, GST Invoice Generation.

Associate Developer

Feb 2014 - Jan 2015

FlexiEle Consulting

Gurgaon

- Worked on internal application which is a 3 tier structure based on Zend Framework.
- Fixed bugs on existing applications and implemented new features in some applications as guided by the Architect.

Software Developer IBM India Pvt Ltd

Jul 2012 - Jan 2014

Bangalore

- Debugging Java codes, Documentation of business processes and troubleshooting solutions.
- Had written shell script running on servers like passwordless authentication.
- Basic Linux administration tasks (user-id creation, password reset, server restart, software installations).

Education

HBTI, Kanpur - 74.23% Master of Computer Application 2009 - 2012

Lucknow University, Lucknow - 60.67% Graduation (BSc Computer Science)

2005 - 2008